hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
talk about ways that you can grow your
coaching business your mentoring
business creating online courses and how
to impact people on a much deeper level
and create an incredible income at the
same time while doing that now today I
want to talk about making the decision
on what software is best to use and what
I want to do is I want to start with an
example a diagram that I'm going to a
draw up here to explain where some
people struggle when it comes to
software if you've been online for any
length of time you know that there are
so many different kinds of software that
we have access to that's being marketed
to you sold to the best this the better
that everything's this this has the
feature oh this is the answer to
everything you've been looking for and
we've even built multiple Industries in
our stock market it's propped up on
better better better growing and impr
improving over time the problem is this
can get into our mind and cause us to
question what it takes to actually get
started in a business and which software
to use the belief that things can get
better if I just move over to something
else and then shiny object syndrome is a
real thing where something new comes
along some new methods some new
technique things like that in fact
that's really what I what I want to talk
about in depth here and we go deeper
into it I want to help you make a
decision of what software to use I want
to help you decide which path to take in
your business but I also want you to
realize that shiny object syndrome in
general is not necessarily a healthy
thing I believe that we can improve
things over time iteratively but what
you wait to do can only hurt you let me
explain this so a lot of people think
that if they they just get everything
perfect they use the perfect software
they use the perfect system platform the
perfect way to do everything that that's
going to produce the best results and
it's not in fact study show and well my
own experience of working with thousands
of coaches and mentors show that in fact
not only is this not wise it actually is
probably the most detrimental thing that
you can do and yet it's what most people
think is the best thing to do so we have
a problem here is that the best
choice and what do we Define as the best
choice the best choice for a mentor and
Coach is what I believe has the highest
level of impact for your clients and
produces the highest amount of revenue
for your business and we Define it by
these two metrics right here okay client
impact and results I I believe not all
all coaching coaching programs or
mentorship are made the same way and not
all coaches are capable of producing
impact transformation and getting
results for their clients they simply
don't know how they can fake it they can
try but they missed the
mark and then finances is really an
important part about
it because you can increase your impact
and the scale of the amount of people
that you reach simply by dialing
in the finances so that you have more
resources to spend you know I have a
video game that I play It's called The
Battle for polytopia don't shut your
mind off because I mentioned that it's a
video game in the game you grow in
resources and you can beat the game
simply by maximizing your economy what
most people don't realize is that this
is how business works as well and yet we
live in a world right now that is so
focused in on being the best doing the
best and doing the best by all people
okay so I'm not going to go into a
socioeconomic debate around that but I
simply believe that optimizing for
profit is actually how you have the most
amount of impact okay the problem with
this is that most people are looking for
software platforms they're looking for
training programs mentorship programs
they're looking for systems gosh you go
out there and shop for a car these days
you look for a house and they're looking
for the cheapest and
best and when it comes to building a
business they're also looking for the
easiest and simplest and so most people
are looking for something that's simply
does not exist on Planet
Earth the
cheapest the
best
and the simplest when it comes to use
you know we I I can think about this
when it comes to um buying a house for
example right the cheapest
house is often not going to be the best
or the simplest there's going to need to
be repairs right
the best house by no means is ever going
to be the cheapest but it could be the
simplest sometimes and the most simplest
TurnKey thing well often times it may
not be the best it may be the easiest to
get into and it may also not be the
cheapest okay that's not necessarily the
best example but I want to use that
example when it comes to software okay
so a lot of people I find they're trying
to balance features
benefits cost
Simplicity having the best features and
generally marketers will utilize say
ours is better than the competitor the
problem is they're all basically saying
that they're better and people are
usually looking for better and simpler
but that often doesn't align with being
cheaper okay and so when it comes to
software here's my rule of thumb when it
comes to business here's my rule of
thumb when it comes
to most things in life I think this is
our rule of
thumb you know I can look at uh
upgrading computers and and and cell
phones and things like that the one that
you use consistently that you show up to
use
consistently is often times the best one
that you can choose it may not be the
best on the
market it may not be the the the
cheapest but it's the one that you can
use and what I find is often the
case most coaches and mentors that I
meet most people that are out there uh
they are massively
overwhelmed by the complexity of most
things and the way that it goes usually
is they're setting out to build a
business and they're sitting on their
idea for so long because of
complexity
there's a book that I read called
Extreme ownership by Joo willink how the
US Navy Seals lead and win and he talks
about the fact that it's removing
features removing
complexity that actually produces the
best results oftentimes the best does
not include the most
complete and I find that when it comes
to course creators and coaches what
we're striving for and looking for is to
have the most complete package it does
everything it saves us the most amount
of money it has all the features and
then somebody else pops up and they do
this so there's really two factors that
I want to discuss here number one
deciding on which platform to use okay
I'll tell you this there's really a very
simple
Matrix when it comes to what most people
prioritize things around which is cost
okay and so often
times cost and
simplicity
are almost a directly opposing moving
scale okay so often
times as cost goes up for software when
it comes to building your business for
systems and things like that the
Simplicity comes
down
okay I guess the complexity
yeah the complexity comes down okay so
it can cost more but it'll be less
complex it'll actually be more simple
cost and simplicity I guess would rise
in the same direction complexity would
come down as cost comes down such as
like the cheapest softwares and things
like that the
complexity goes up and the
Simplicity goes down why because often
times what we're actually paying for is
shrinking
timelines and in business that is really
what creates most of the businesses that
we live in today is what creates
efficiency what shrinks down the amount
of time that it takes to get from point
A to point B okay and so often times
people are willing to in the in the
marketplace pay for
Simplicity now you can make the argument
that capitalism as a whole is a Scourge
on the earth and it's the problem as to
why things cost so much for Simplicity I
actually believe that they're it's a
great thing it's an incredible vehicle
and the alternative uh Marxism and
communism are not good options for us
why and you might say well Jeremiah
don't you care about other people of
course in fact I think that capitalism
is one of the best vehicles to raise
people out of poverty to improve their
lives overall long term in fact evidence
shows this over the last couple hundred
years uh you know close to 95% of the
population was in poverty until
capitalism came in and that comes down
to about 5% okay so the marketplace the
fact that
cost is a factor related to Simplicity
which sometimes people see as
gatekeeping and there's there's gosh
there's so many arguments as to why you
can get so angry at all of this I would
just say listen if you're feeling angry
and upset by the way the world
is that's a distraction in
life and and it's distracting you from
being effective okay and so I'm not
going to even really have that
conversation i' I've I've actually come
to a a place in my life where I don't
argue with people that are just angry at
how the world is and and and just think
that everything should just be better
than it really is and it's just so bad
and all that like those aren't people
that I'm looking for I'm looking for
people that have optimism people that
are seeing things the world as the glass
half full not half empty and in fact
while there might be great people that
see the world that way and they have
their place
um they're not people that I want to
hang around and as a coach or Mentor I
think that they can be more of a drain
on your business overall because I think
that we need to have optimism and I
think that we need to think
optimistically instead of out of a
scarcity mindset I think that we need to
think out of abundance and not that of
oh man things are not so good and and
start to actually think in a way that is
aligned with what what going to actually
get us our results can I tell you this
expecting things to go well for you is a
good way of thinking Some people see it
as delusional some people may argue that
you are confident in things that aren't
true I'm sorry but any sort of logical
framework that people come up with as to
why this is uh while their arguments may
make sense in reality when you actually
go to apply them for Effectiveness they
crumble and they don't actually produce
results they actually work and so really
what I find that the most effective
thing is is to keep an optimistic
Outlook even when things don't go how we
quote unquote think they should okay so
when it comes to cost when it comes to
capitalism when it comes to the
marketplace when it comes to software
when it comes to all of these things
when it comes to our frustration in life
can we talk about that can we talk about
the frustration that we existentially
feel when things don't go how we want
that's a choice it's a choice to think
differently as well and it's a choice to
see things differently and so often
times what I encourage people to do is
this they are in a constant Pursuit for
better more optimized cheaper and
simpler all at the same time and they're
seeking something that is unreasonable
and
unrealistic and I I am a firm believer
in having very big goals while
simultaneously shrinking them down to
the present moment of what is reality
okay and so what I love to look at is
let's dream massively big what what
would be the best case scenario in all
fronts this utopian vision of everything
right okay now we come back down to
reality and we look at how can we just
get one step further than where we are
right now and that's what I that's how I
like to look at life that's how I like
to look at uh product development in
fact you know if we look
at what could be and then what is often
times just improving by one degree is
actually all that's needed in creating
products and that's actually how a lot
of the products that we have exist 10 15
20 years from now with AI extrapolated
out I guarantee
you a lot of what I'm saying in this
podcast is not even going to be relevant
I think that you will have the best and
cheapest and simplest and marketing is
going to look so different in 15 to 20
years from now that uh half of what I
teach is going to be completely
irrelevant but knowing myself I will
keep you up to date and I'll make sure
that you know how to stay ahead of the
curve and have a cutting edge advantage
over the world around us okay and so
here's one of the things that I want to
encourage you
with stop seeking the cheapest option
okay now I understand if you are coming
out of complete poverty you have no
money whatsoever you can't even pay the
bills or anything okay cheapest option
might be
great um because it can pull you out of
poverty there's actually a platform
right now that's out there it's called
system IO and um using system IO is
pretty cool because you can actually get
a free account with them and it's not a
gimmick when they say that it's free
it's actually like legitimately free
I've used the free account and they they
really give you a lot of incredible
tools I think it's I think it's really
cool what they provide you with and the
the um
like the depth of what they actually
give you for free is is amazing okay and
so in this
however
um realize that as you grow most people
are going to need their $27 tier as far
as this goes okay now you look at a
software that's out there like
kajabi
kajabi is priced at 400 dollar a month
as far as this goes this I would
consider one of the best platforms that
are out there but they're not the
cheapest um there is one that I think is
pretty cool it's called go high level um
it is probably one of the best overall
but the
complexity is crazy because of how much
it
does and I find that a lot of people get
really addicted to this chart right here
around what things do and they want it
to do everything and they are more
excited about the fact that it does
everything than what they can do with it
and so this is why I encourage most
people that when they're marketing their
business not to seek after the cheapest
option but to seek after what is going
to save them time and effort and delays
and
procrastination and so oftentimes as a
coach and Mentor what we need to really
optimize is for our own procrastination
habits now you can can justify
procrastination all you want whether it
be a spirit of Excellence or wisdom or
the need to um you know do everything
right and all that again I understand
maybe that's your
personality uh but at the end of the day
I can tell you this as somebody who has
been in this industry for a long time
things evolve very quickly and and the
problem is is that by the time you learn
everything um something else has come
along and so speed I believe is
important we need to prioritize speed
when it comes to building a business
especially today especially in a world
with artificial intelligence and what I
mean by speed is speed to actually get
something up in your business now
oftentimes this causes anxiety in people
because they feel like well what if it's
not good enough what if it's not better
enough and we keep going back to this
Loop of believing that things need to be
at some certain arbitrary level of
perfection before it's good enough to
put out there publicly to the rest of
the world can I tell you this doesn't
matter it literally doesn't matter um
what matters most is getting something
up getting something going connecting
with a group of people what I would
rather you do simply
put gather a hundred people in front of
you maybe 200 in a zoom call or on a
recorded video and teach them something
now here's the now here's the thing in a
in a group of 100 to 200 people chances
are that about 5 to 10 of them strongly
disagree with what you're going to teach
and actually feel like they have a
better way and they want to tell you
that you're wrong exists you're going to
have a lot of people that say that
that's a
huge common thing so then a lot of
people shrink back and they wait until
everything's
perfect they don't do anything the
problem though that I see more often
than not is people do nothing and they
sit around with this mindset of I'm
going to make it better I'm and improve
it it's going to come and become better
over time long term things are going to
improve and then someday I'm going to
arrive to where I finally feel good
enough to put things out there to where
the risk of criticism and disappointing
others is so low that then I finally
feel confident enough to launch my
business and many times this is
connected to a belief that confidence is
tied to what we do and quote
unquote absolute truth uh versus the
process of doing things over time
confidence in business is a lot more
like learning to ride a
bike you have to get on the bike and
fall
down and skin your knee and by doing
that enough times you'll get confident
enough to reach your goals many people
are waiting until they've studied enough
and they feel good enough and they've
they've tested it all out with for free
before they actually put something out
there and start charging money for it
and really what this is is this would be
the mindset of a child who's waiting
until they're an expert uh you know
Motocross rider before they even get on
a
tricycle you know that in fact that
thinking is delusional and I don't mean
this to be harsh to anybody but a lot of
people are actually operating in what
they believe is wisdom and it's actually
very much delusional thinking is that
that someday things are going to get so
good that they'll finally be ready yet
the truth is is that there's always room
for improvement and SO waiting until
things are perfect before you put
something out there is not wisdom in
fact it's probably one of the worst
things that you can do uh in my
experience there are many people that
will argue against what I've just said
um they'll they'll
argue and and I even know based on what
I'm saying there are some people that
think that what I'm telling you is just
a justification for apathy and launching
lowquality products that all they do is
produce disappointment
and hurt people and are just
contributing to the ever growing noise
of low quality driil that's out there in
the world I disagree with that and I
actually think that if you have an
intention to make impact and income your
goal you'll reach your results and so
what that takes is what allows you when
it comes to your software because that's
what this is about what does it take for
you to actually be consistent
and not procrastinate okay and that's
the point that I've been trying to get
to here I took a long way to get here we
took the long route we took the scenic
route uh but I'm I'm making a point for
the fact that
sometimes you may want to use a software
that costs just a little bit
more but improves the
Simplicity by exponential
amounts and that also comes when it
comes to possibly even
hiring people you may want to spend just
a little bit more money to hire somebody
to do something so that you're not
trying to figure it out totally on your
own when it comes to Facebook ads as a
way to do this hiring a mentor for a fee
like we have my accelerator program you
know we have our coaching program and we
have our training and what that does is
when people hire me as a mentor and
Coach it saves them time and it
accelerates how quickly they can
actually start to get results and that's
what our clients see is they go from
struggling to things starting to come
together for them you know often times I
I have clients they tell me Jeremiah
I've tried everything I tried every
course every program every possible way
to be successful until I came to you and
uh and then I started working with you
and I saw results and that lights me up
because it it tells me it proves every
single client success story validates
improves our system even more and I love
hearing stories like that now is every
client that I have a million dollar
success story No in fact I have clients
that have been in my program for a year
and haven't made a
dime oh no Jeremiah does that mean that
you're not legit how can you think that
that's ethical right some people think
that that's an ethical flaw on my part
to allow them to stay in there I talked
with the lady about this the other day
and she said here's the thing Jeremiah
my business hasn't grown but every other
part of my life has and I finally feel
confident enough to put myself there and
I didn't know what I didn't know when I
got started with you and now I actually
really feel ready to do things so I know
that some people may go through a
journey where it takes them the long way
to feel confident to reach their goals I
meet a lot of people that are that are
like that they have so much potential
they have so much incredible things that
they could do to impact people they
could change the world and yet they're
sitting on their goals because because
of the need to feel good enough about it
can I tell you this often times we don't
feel peaceful about the moves that we
need to make often times they feel risky
often times they feel stressful often
times they feel like a
struggle but when we step out when we
take a leap of faith when we say you
know what I might not have it all
figured out but I'm going to jump and
build the parachute as I fall down and
can I tell you this that can be scary
I'm not going to negate that fact that
could be terrifying in fact for some
people but growing in the confidence to
where you don't let that fear stop you
and you actually learn to become
comfortable with what felt scary can I
tell you this that often times what it
takes to be successful is doing the
thing that feels the most terrifying and
actually starting to embrace what felt
terrifying at one time to where it
actually feels very exciting for you you
know me making this podcast used to be
terrifying when I started started I used
to have to take shots of alcohol just to
even have the confidence to talk with
you and now you know I haven't drank in
years and I feel great sharing and
sharing from my heart and and expanding
on Big Ideas and and and and I'm not
worried about how anybody's going to
take it or perceive it or if it's going
to land wrong or things like that or or
the perception I do not concern myself
with the perception of what other people
think about me at all do do I concern
myself with coming across understandably
not overwhelming people being way too
complex of course but that's an
iterative process and that's something
that I'm improving on over time you know
some of you are listening to this
episode maybe you've listened to other
podcasts of mine maybe you're making a
judgment either what I've talked about
was too complex and you're like Jeremiah
you could have gotten to your point
quicker okay great awesome probably
could have I'm going to get better
others of you are like wow that was so
much more concise than I've ever heard
you teach and that's the thing you're
not going to please everybody you're not
going to be the favorite flavor of the
week for everybody people love Apple
people love Android but what you're
going to be is you're going to be the
right person for the people that
absolutely love working with you and
what that is is people who their fire is
lit up simply by being in your presence
so hopefully if you're listening to this
podcast right now you are somebody whose
fire is lit up by listening to
me if that's the case I would love to
invite you to join me on some of our
live events that we're hosting I'd love
to invite you to join me in my
accelerator program when we open the do
to it and I want to encourage you in
this again when it comes to choosing the
best software you notice I didn't
necessarily tell you what the best
software to use is I'll tell you what my
favorite is for most people if if maybe
you've been looking for this at the end
of this my favorite
is
Squarespace why do I like Squarespace
because it's the it's in my opinion the
best balance between cost and simplicity
for most people to use for most people
to figure out out if you can use
Microsoft Word you can use Squarespace
to launch a funnel to launch your
marketing to get clients and to sell
things now there are other tools that
are out there you know we're exploring
some of them um I'm taking a look at
them uh but I still haven't found
anything that has changed my mind about
being on Squarespace you know we started
back in the day doing pure HTML I
remember I built my first website on
HTML I coded everything this was
actually when I was 7 years old and and
a lot of people don't know that part of
my story some of you like wow this is
easy for you cuz you've been coding
since you were a kid yeah I I have been
and I I understand that but like you
know um that was hard you know we had to
build websites by like and we use a tool
that you could drag and drop and but it
would create code and you had to know
the code and all that then WordPress
came up and you could at least it had a
a a a structure that was easier to use
and then there was visual editors that
popped up for WordPress then all these
platforms came up to where basically
they would run the logistics behind the
scenes of all the teex stuff and they
would just give you access to all the
tools the problem is now a lot of those
have ballooned in their complexity and
more and simpler tools are popping up
every single day I'll tell you this I
love that I think it's great I think new
simple tools are great but here's the
problem if you're going from tool to
tool to Tool because you have shiny
object syndrome and you can't seem to
commit to one thing that's a problem and
it's not helping you and so what I would
encourage you to do is commit to using
something commit to using a tool commit
to one niche in your business commit to
one possible marketing plan one coach
One
Mentor and see what happens after 6
months to a year instead of jumping away
Jumping Ship after just a couple of
months of things getting hard realize
that maybe you can grow in these ways
and maybe just maybe things can get
better I'll encourage you use what's the
simplest of tools overall it's always
worth worth it however as well if cost
is a problem you
know you can find cheaper stuff that's
out there but it's going to be harder
for you to use if you're looking for the
most features it's probably not the
simplest to use even if it's the best
thing even if it's even if it's the best
you want to find what's best for you and
what's best for you may not be the best
for somebody else and that's often times
what we really need to realize that is
that it's really about individual best
you know for some people playing video
games is a bad thing for some people it
would hurt them it would damage their
family there's people that see it as
irresponsible to their families to play
video games for me playing video games
is actually part of my creative process
as a business owner and I've actually
integrated it into my day and structure
to include video game playing time some
people would see that as wow you're
neglecting your wife and kids for doing
that no I'm not in fact I'm providing a
better life for them by playing video
games and I hold to that belief and it's
something that there's nobody that can
ever change Chang my mind on that
anymore I've had people try uh but I I
see the fruit of it I see the fruit in
the lives of my clients my ability to
serve them my ability to build my
business is the more I play video games
the better everything is and it's just
it's it's an irrefutable fact that that
I've been trying to prove wrong for
probably the last oh 10 years and I it
just I seem to become more and more
solidified in that belief and and and my
wife always encourages me that if I'm
struggling to be creative she's like go
play a video game she's like go go play
some m
go play some polytopia go play something
like that and so can I tell you this
that what works best for an individual
may not be the best for somebody else
but we got to figure out what
individually works best for us okay and
what works best for us is often what
serves to not encourage
procrastination what serves to not
encourage us taking longer to get things
done efficiency is great and I think
that it's an important thing speed in
business is important and I think that
you can combine speed impact income and
produce massive results with people by
taking what I call an iterative alpha
release approach to building your course
mentorship or membership business this
is the last point that I'm going to
share on this an alpha release approach
is this in the software world it's
called releasing an underdevelopment
version of software that's used for
initial testing which means that it's in
the early stage what I want you to do in
your business is you might not have
everything complete to put out there to
launch but it might have one or two
features that can impact people and you
might know that I can improve it over
time there's no lack of Integrity by you
releasing that and being 100% honest and
transparent about the fact that hey
we're improving this over time sure
might some people not like it they might
not trust you they might even demonize
and condemn you for it but you got to
stop worrying about what other people
think stop trying to not disappoint
people stop trying to do everything
perfect and realize that consistency
over time time is what produces the very
best results in our business if you can
stay consistent at putting stuff out
there at reaching people at finding the
people that need a specific thing that
you can help them with that can build
you a multi six and S figure business
and I would challenge you on this money
solves all your problems if you increase
your
Revenue to $40 to $60,000 a
month you have no problems in your
business whatsoever today or your life
you can literally live live pretty much
anywhere uh in just about any type of
house you want uh have team members that
run everything for you uh not be in debt
up to your ears uh have an incred like
go out to eat whenever you want do all
that and you're not even necessarily
making a million dollars a year but
you're making enough that you have
options and you can speed up how long it
takes you to get to the next level and
you can buy Simplicity you can buy
access to knowledge you can buy access
to skill
sets one of the things that we need to
do is realize that we need to increase
our income in our world today the
economy is not getting better and things
are getting more expensive increasing
your income is a must for the
future and I will tell you this that my
business grew when I stopped trying to
be the cheapest when I stopped trying to
be cheap when I stopped trying to only
use cheap things and when I started to
be willing to pay just a little bit more
for Simplicity you know I used to buy
the cheapest cars that had the best
features but they would break all the
time and I started paying just a little
bit more for a car that had a warranty
that I could make sure feel confident
putting my wife and son in that it
wouldn't break down on them on the road
and that we could take it in somewhere
to have it fixed there are some people
that share an opinion that that's
completely financially
irresponsible but it was the best for me
and it worked and I feel confident and I
actually think that that choice that I
made uh in 20 2020 to buy a Dodge Ram uh
that had a great warranty on it that you
know we knew we were going to get
pregnant we we were planning for the
future of this in fact you know my wife
didn't get pregnant for two more years
after that but it was actually about a
year and a half after that but we were
planning for that when we actually
purchased that vehicle and that's what
we thought is we wanted something that I
knew would be simple because we were
done with dealing with cars that were
breaking down all the time and I grew up
in a household where you know breaking
down a car and fixing it all the time
and all that was a way of life and and
in fact I I have the knowledge to
literally strip a motor down and rebuild
it I know how to do that I've done it
before a couple times uh but it was a
distraction from my calling which was to
build a business to be successful and
can I tell you this my income has gone
up and my life has changed and yours can
as well when you learn to just a have
more fun in life
B just do what works best for you and
figure out what you can optimize for
that doesn't create
procrastination and allows you to move
the needle forward it's a little bit
faster than you already are right now
instead of just going from zero to 100
doing The Compound Effect where you go
from 0 to 1 and then 1 to 3 and then 3
to 6 6 to 9 9 to 12 and compounding over
time improving over time an iterative
process that's how our lives change
that's how our lives improve
oftentimes sure making giant massive
changes can do a lot of stuff but it's
not necessarily always sustainable and
so when you can figure out what can I
sustain it may not be perfect you could
have room for improvement but embracing
that room for improvement as
a great thing and a beautiful thing
that's where greatness comes from all
right so I hope this encourages you I
hope it inspires you and if you're still
listening to this make sure to share it
with somebody make sure to plug in
subscribe follow me I have new episodes
every single week that have great ideas
and incredible advice and I think you'll
really like them we host Live Events uh
all the time to help coaches mentors
people create membership sites and
recurring income for themselves so you
can have a consistent an income of $40
to $60,000 a month I think that that's
incredible right I it's I think it's a
great place to get to that's between a
half a million to
$750,000 a year and that's life-changing
money right there even if you're not at
that level and you just want to maybe
make 50 to 100,000 I'll show you how to
get there all right so grow your life
we'll talk soon have a good
[Music]
[Applause]
one